watching pool so a solution racing is an
hour-long conversation we bring
ourselves that are biased everything
else to the conversations so all of your
experience everything that you bring but
the idea is to generate something new
not necessarily hold on to something we
had before coming to the conversation so
this is to run parallel to the
conversation game be had last week
although both of you attended you're
welcome to bring what was what happened
there into the conversation but it is it
I wasn't there that's why I can't build
on what was done there it's like
parallel and anyone can watch it and
decide what they want to get out of
mapping game B this issue has come up
consistently in game B is how do you map
it how does somebody new understand it
how does this is the first time we've
done a solution raising on game beats
specifically where people who aren't
maybe it wouldn't be able to really
participate so we spend 15 minutes
talking about what's currently being
done 15 minutes talking about what we
would like an art ideal version of the
future and then we spend half an hour
usually talking about we could do the
10,000 people and $100,000 for this
particular solution raising because game
he doesn't have 10,000 people and we're
focusing on game B I'm gonna say with a
thousand people and $10,000 also with
the ingenuity that's in game B right I
think there are people who are willing
to do some of the labor for free so we
don't need to if I have $100,000 so I'm
going to change in the parameter so it's
something that could happen in game
because again we don't have 10,000
people and what we could still stick
with $100,000 but then would be everyone
putting in $100 I think this a little
we'll play with that when we get there
so for the first part we're talking
about what is Curt what is getting map
being game B currently look like and why
it keeps being a topic that we need we
need to talk about so you can each take
a turn to share or you can pass it you
don't want to share for that for that
portion then we can have an open
discussion for the remainder of that
time and when it feels right transfer on
to the next part of the conversation
again the first 15 minutes or other 10
minutes about we'll be talking about
what is currently being done to math
game B and why we feel we need something
different
currently what's good and bad about
what's being done
either you would like to start since I
wasn't there last week I don't actually
know it's currently being done and it's
gonna talk okay so what is currently
being done I am to be honest not sure
apart from Adrian's quick project mmm
least application but apart from that I
did not find any specific like
encompassing all-encompassing library or
catalogue of projects groups individuals
and I understand that it's because first
there is no clear definition of what
Lane B is and what criteria there are
for a define and determining if
something is then B is something between
there named a Lane a game B and yeah
there is that and and yeah as much as we
don't want to define it and write in
stone what exactly we are looking for
and what exactly is going be in I guess
the concern there are many concerns
about it so we don't want this but at
the same time the projects that are out
there are real and you would very much
like to know about them and have some
sort of like overview maybe not
necessarily of mmm like everything from
a specific angle but more like we would
like to know what is out there in very
general terms so what is currently
banana I know of several projects that
are in a beta stage to be said that
there are many people working on this
and I did see along those years
phew
designs of few descriptions of what such
a system would look like but as I am
aware there is nothing written yet so
James you wanna share um yeah I probably
I feel like I'm also not aware of
probably a lot of the stuff that's going
on related to Macri at the moment but
that does seem to be quite a lot of it
popping up and it was really interesting
in the call last week to see some of the
projects actually kind of connect into
the game be space who are working on
different tools that are kind of related
to the subject of mapping so one example
is a group called the brain and just to
clarify this because it can be confusing
there's actually two different mind
mapping tools called the brain but
they're both felt slightly differently
the original one is spelled like the the
normal way you'd spell the brain and the
new one which the guys who are involved
with j-b
it's spelled like BR ane like like
membrane or something and yeah they're
doing some really interesting work
there's also some some interesting
people who kind of came along you've
just been involved in mind mapping for a
long time using for example at the old
version of the brain and tools like Kumu
to kind of plot out you know just even
just from a kind of a personal
perspective just to map out the
different things that they are
interested in their life to kind of keep
track of stuff different links that they
come across different projects they're
interested in and to kind of organize it
in a framework that makes it easy for
them to then go and find that
information and navigate through it so
yeah there's a lot of people that kind
of have an interest in this subject it
seems and there's there's definitely
projects kind of moving pushing the ball
forward in that space for me I would say
like the value of mapping is that it's
it's actually relevant to a lot of
different areas so whenever you have a
situation where there's a landscape of
some kind that's that's very complex and
filled with lots of different data and
you're trying to make sense of that what
I think I'm the value of a map is that
it kind of takes all that complexity and
reduces it down to a simple model that's
much easier to comprehend and has the
kind of key bits of information that you
need to be able to navigate that
landscape so that could be you know in a
rebase ik sense that could be like a
physical landscape with just like a you
know a paper map that visualizes where
the mountains are the villages and the
roads or it could be you know mapping
something a bit more ephemeral like a
social network and visualizing different
communities and different types of
connections within that space that if
you didn't have a map to visualize that
would be very difficult to pick up on
and especially to code and navigate
through so I think there's there's a lot
of value in maps for that kind of reason
but to me this is what I was kind of
bringing up in the call last week what
I'm most excited about with mapping is
how it can be how people can collaborate
around shared Maps because I think like
part of the way that our brains work is
that we the way we understand reality in
the world around us is that we build
maps out of the information that we we
take it and kind of build models within
our minds so we're already I think
naturally wired to be able to build maps
and to do that in a very kind of dynamic
flexible way but I think what we lack at
the moment is the ability to build maps
in that same kind of way but
collectively in large groups that are
often dispersed you know across huge
distances so I think that's where that
real potential lies in the future is if
we can kind of develop tools that enable
groups that are coordinating around any
different subject to be able to kind of
come together and add their little
pieces of data that they each have from
their perspectives and have that kind of
synthesized in a shared map that takes
in all that information and provide
something that's very useful to everyone
in terms of kind of coordinating finding
out what's going on and knowing where to
add their contributions so to me it's
like
there's a real exciting potential that
to level up group collective
intelligence through designing the right
tools thank you I will try to take only
a couple minutes to do it to do mine
about the game be space is very
interesting to map because one we don't
even know what game B is you don't know
where we're going we don't have you
transition to it we don't we there's
many people who have ideas on how we do
that but masking those and figuring out
how do you do your individual piece to
make sense but in doing so not like I
want my sense to add to the sense making
of the group not dissipate it and right
now because there's so many people come
into the game's peace space and they're
confused what's going on what is game B
so I pretend you can answer that
question let alone what is happening
here who's involved what are the
projects and so there's a handful of
tools
what is game B some of us it's the
conversation or some of us it's the
personal work some of us it's the
project work and I think it's all of the
above so to be able to have somebody
come and be new and be like right
where's the gas station you need to pull
out the map and say here's where we are
and here's where we need to go and
because we don't have that we don't
really I think we need to take a step
back and brainstorm what we would want
mapped before we ever map and the PERT
the problem is is everyone's writing
their own map and it's never really
gonna be able to be used by somebody
else because we orient differently there
is no north-south east-west here's the
gas station here's here's how you get
there it's well my version of game B is
this we do this with currency and this
with governance and it's okay if you're
is this different but we're going
towards that and what is the next step
and so having the conversation like I
was just writing down here in the game B
space they gave you Facebook groups
there's already three that really are
mapping there's game B wiki which is
dealing with all the same things but I
came to a standstill because the idea of
the wiki is that it does all this stuff
right it's the tools it tells us what
projects it tell us with people there's
together tech which I'm involved in
Patricius is is involved in of okay so
we're bringing our projects together and
figure you know how can we create all
new in solutions for our project so they
can get out in the world but the same
issues keep coming up of how do you know
what's going on how do you under
Alma can be is and I think it isn't one
documents it is a bunch of kind of
understanding of definitions and there's
multiple definitions for each word and
multiple courses and to honor and truly
get that there's complexity and no
single map can actually be the full
thing and so there's gonna be things
other people have on their map that you
don't have on yours because you don't
care about gas stations you don't drive
by date and there's other things that
we're gonna have that or comment and so
that to me is right now it feels
confusing to be a new person and game be
even not being a new person game be like
when you come in it's like well what's
going on where can I be what can what is
what conversations can I attend what
conversations can i watch what projects
can I be part of how do I create a
project how do we create project
together how do we work through even not
being together right and so this is a
very fertile ground for complexity and
mapping complexity and working through
this as a group and having it be that
there's all this different stuff
happening like there's missing there's a
wiki there's the map newer mapping
Facebook group and there's also
technology tools which are kind of
looking at what's already out there that
we can use in game B but I feel like
they come up constantly right like the
conversation generator and the
scheduling app and there's certain
things that are tools that a few people
and you try to understand what projects
are happening what people and mapping
that and it feels like we never get
beyond beta because there's so many
betas like it's like none of them are
hurt or the thing and I don't know if
many people are mapping but there's a
ton of people who have a project of
projects Janelle has one I can't
remember the name of perhaps you know I
think that's Kylie's one and so there's
all of these different somewhat
competing things and none of them have
resources or the like and this is a good
transition to the next part of the topic
which is what do we want it to look like
and our idea version of the future if we
came together and truly match game beat
whatever that means to us is an
individual what does that look like to
us and this portion of the conversation
doesn't need to match it's not a
democracy if James's version of a map
looks for them and - sizzles - friend of
mine that's totally fine it's what could
it look like right it's the elephant
we're all feeling different pieces and
instead of arguing about
right it's like putting those pieces
together to get the elephant this in for
this solution racing even more so than
the rest so whoever would like to share
their version of what their ideal
version of mapping game B looks like in
the future whether that's tomorrow or
five years ago I think I liked what you
said like I think a really key part is
that when people come to game B it's
just having a very clear roadmap of like
how to find our way to what's going on
so that they can actually find their way
into these different subjects and if
they've got you know if they've got some
kind of gem that they've got to give
just making sure that it's very easy for
them to find where they're most
appropriate place where that is to be
shared and I've just noted down here a
couple things like to me an ideal map
would would one aspect would be that
it's kind of fractal so you could have
knit kind of high level map it takes you
to the main sections of game B then as
you navigate down to those areas it's
like a fractal and you could kind of go
down to some more smaller smaller
details so I think in that sense you
could actually have a single overarching
map that kind of integrates all the
different smaller and smaller areas that
you could find within game B another
aspect of it for me that I think would
be really key is is making it as
flexible as possible so kind of going
back to your point that you know if if
we're to keep creating kind of separate
Maps but they're very much like
customized to our preferences then their
value to other people is going to be
quite limited so if we can create maps
that have the give users the ability to
kind of customize how they're viewed so
that they can kind of they can highlight
different aspects of the map maybe that
they're interested in and you know even
down to things like potentially even
customizing the UI so they can actually
see it in a different way I think that
would make it more accessible to a wider
range of people so yes those two aspects
come to mind
it's hard to tell what should be on the
map because who because we are not 100%
sure what it is we are mapping so I also
wanted to point out that that's
important what we don't map and what we
leave out of the big picture
well scene could be okay what I loved it
what I thought it could start with in
the most simple way so users who are new
to the space are not lost immediately in
the you know forest of ideas ideologies
and high-level descriptions of what is
wrong with they may and what needs to be
done like for example many people who
come to the space do come here because
they perceive something being around
with capitalism and they are very anti
something so they would expect a map of
tools to destroy some economic system as
they see being not fit to rule the world
and it's not third so if I wanted to
start small I'll start with set of
well-defined problems that can be
ascribed to like can be viewed as game
be solutions or ideas but at the same
time that not necessarily need this
whole concept of the envy being present
at all it for example we know that food
and water are problematic especially in
certain parts of the world so if there
was a webpage describing various ideas
about how to clean water that would be
gained be on one hand as we see them be
but on the other hand
for someone who is new they would see
okay this is solution for one particular
problem that we can all agree that it is
the problem it is real and it can be
dealt with in local communities in
open-source way and generally yeah like
using non game a solutions and ways of
dealing with problems so that would be
one thing and then it could be that
there are just few groups of problems
that we need to deal with and like I
said something like before the bottom of
Maslow's pyramid food water shelter
communication electricity like power
stuff like that and they all have their
own define sets of subproblems and it
all can fractally expand from like okay
we need there's problem with power as in
electricity and then there are solutions
and just open like a tree like no flower
tree and it could be visualized in of
course 3d space as we discussed on this
big big meeting about mapping and yeah
the brain one or the other and various
other solutions that deal with mapping
they will be very useful in this in this
area but they are not complete enough to
to be sufficient to like not only
visualize everything but only have
additional okay I'm getting ahead of
myself I think that because details not
needed at this point so yeah fractal
tree like structure that's what I would
like to see and that is what would be
the least confusing to new people
because it would start with okay the
problem is water and solutions ABCD and
then each of the solutions will have
their own set of like more and more
detailed way of explaining so my person
I'm Jane be mapped in my NGO world is
the technology cooperative it is not
know my game B but it be gave me the
language around it it's having somebody
be able to come in have their own
individual unique map based on who they
are where can they find their most where
can they find their teams of people how
can they find what projects would most
be useful for them vote that they would
get the most benefit being on that team
and also the team would most be able to
use them what I was doing here and Ryan
was this idea between its map so having
where we are we might be in conflict
with but that we're starting somewhere
and we're trying to understand this
thing called capitalism this thing
called game and this thing called
history and we might absolutely
different-- what's broken about what
right now but that's okay we also might
differ on what game B actually is what
does constitute game B I think it's all
of these interlocking circles that are
different depending on who you are so
for me it's all new in solutions it's
concentrating on the anti rival
resolutions that actually getting better
the more people are involved the
scalability and being a natural
attractor and out competing game a at
it's in its own its own field for other
people it's not all it's part of that
but not all of that and so for me game B
is kind of the sweet spot of long by
Venn diagrams but really game B is is
all of our interpret actually circles
together and showcasing like what James
had to say that having to be
individualistic the UI being what I see
can be in develop individualized me but
understanding the complexity I don't
almost like a choose-your-own-adventure
like here's where I think we're broken
right like like my version of the map
could be where we're starting where I
want to get to and then the many
different paths they could get us there
it's somehow mapping that so that the
individual has access to their best
information about where we are
how they understand it their best
version of this this idea in the future
of this ideal world we're never going to
get to because utopias aren't possible
because you're maximizing it for your
values the path to getting there is like
this magical just everyone having that
vision and starting from where they are
instead of arguing about where we
starting over yet - we just start moving
it actually weaves together to be game B
but not only show things within the
doing of it it is the different people
working on different projects and
figuring out the the fractured nests of
it it isn't fractal it's fractured and
then making the fractured fractal and
constantly B instead of it being
everyone's dissipated hey where did it
we're why do you feel that you don't
understand what's going on what would
make it make sense to you like having
the feedback in it for what's not
working so that it continually be
improved for everybody and I think that
is a bit of what mine would would look
like that's the best summary I heard
about game B space is just making the
fractured fractal yeah because now we
have all this shards of good wheel
energy skills and they are just not
connected so the way I see this this
project it would be not even there's so
many different aspects of this that it's
one meeting is not going to cover even a
small amount of it but in short there's
not only the mapping aspect the
knowledge of what's out there there is
the connectivity aspect as well there
was this enabling that is talking to
everyone involved who might be involved
would like to be involved and yeah very
exciting yeah but I think there is ways
like we because it hasn't been done
before we look at it like that's a
chaotic mess that can never happen like
these conversations never happen until
they did right we're able to come up
with a possible
adjacent possible that we could create
right now with 10,000 people at $100,000
just having the conversation showcasing
it's possible right well like once
you're able to run this is a five-minute
mile then everyone was here not everyone
but a lot of people are able to break
the five-minute mile that how mean
people showcase what is possible creates
the idea that's possible cuz game be is
complex right having everyone have food
everyone have water every one of
electricity everyone have these on you
in solutions we have different ideas on
how to get there yeah I do think we have
a cop fairly common if if we had let's
say a hundred game B people brainstorm
what are all the things that we need a
place for you to be living your game B
we would see that although none of us
have exactly the same we all have very
common overlapping ones like having an a
tool to assess how do we get water how
do we get food that the best way for
ourselves right having their information
that's accessible and usable on you know
if we're going through pandemic cope in
nineteen but like on climate change on
health care on anything that you're
dealing with having information that's
usable and accessible and so breaking it
down in that way so we can see the
problem and then how many people are
working on solutions and what solution
offers what and can be you know combine
them and just smacking that mapping
where we are and how we get to our
version of maybe gets us all the game
because my version might not include
feeding the world it does but I don't
know why it wouldn't but right I might
think it's less important to educate the
world I want everyone have access
everything it's like active mapping it's
not only knowledge but it's only also
connectivity and I think it's a it's
common mistake too and it's very game a
to think that everyone sorry I'm
connected to some other piece of
information should follow the same
manifesto or the same set of values
everyone is in game gain be actually
expected to do their own thing by their
own rules to some extent maybe on a
foundation of the same set of values
more or less because
the higher order values seem to be very
similar between people like all over the
world but yeah by doing their own thing
feeling on like nish of like I want to
be doing this so I'm doing this and
somehow magically disconnected with
every every scene else let me know
and everyone what everyone else is doing
that by doing their own thing they just
create everyone straight in the den B so
what we need to say like a platform it's
like hmm in the forest that trees like
lots of trees and on the surface like
they are not connected maybe they are
but you know but underneath the surface
there is this whole like mycelium thing
going on it is vast networks of
information and value exchange that can
cover like square miles and I see the
platform being something like something
like this connecting providing
communication means of means of
coordination and cooperation something
like this in the most agnostic way
possible
like no ideology no unforeseen a
specific set of worldviews or values
it's not what it's for it's only for
making cooperation and communication
possible you know I think that is
actually the side that for some reason
because Matthew where we are and where
we need to get to and how we get there
is very different for every individual
and so is sorry I lost my train of
thought
are you just a magician having the tools
I don't remember it was great though
it'll be back if it's meant to but that
was making me think that actually what
you're saying which is that one value of
mapping is that it can can enable it can
be a framework but a name
people to all be acting at they're kind
of individual level doing that the
things that they're interested in and
yet somehow we've those contributions
together so that you get something
emerging at the collective level that
couldn't be achieved by any of you
individuals alone and they may not even
be aware of what that bigger picture is
going to be but by having the right kind
of tools and framework it can actually
weave all these different contributions
together so I think it can be a very
like integrating process and I it's like
the analogy of like similarities to
actually the way our brain works and
that you know we build very complex
models of the world around us and you
know single neuron is not able to hold
the fullness of one of those models it's
only through coordinating those neurons
very effectively that you get this
capacity to build complex models that
transcend by a long way the capabilities
of any individual neurons so I think
that's my kind of like one of my dreams
with mapping is that you know if we can
if we can work out the dynamics and we
can build those kind of basic tools
obviously it's going to start small and
they'll probably be a long period where
it's being tested and refined but once
we get that capacity it's it's there
isn't really any scale limits and it
could be one of those kind of game B
technologies where actually the more
people that participate I mean the value
goes up rather than down looking at
global scale something that you could
have incredibly complex things being
mapped a very quick speed just by having
the right tool that everyone can log on
online can kind of explore the map
that's that's been created already they
can find the areas that where there's
blind spots in the map they can add
their little contributions and
everyone's doing this simultaneously you
just get this this complex landscape
mapped very quickly through everyone's
collaboration yeah never ever thought
which was to what Matisse had said and
who not to deal with this as individuals
right where individuals living our lives
so what does it look like at the
individual as Jubilee how do I have this
moat as much sovereignty as possible the
irony is there's only so much I can do
by myself in sovereignty there's a
certain amount that we have to do
collectively like if I'm
and house and clothes I have more
sovereignty do not rely on my government
to not rely on outside forces and so
keep owning that and looking for place
from where sovereignty and then in
groups looking at okay how does this
group have sovereignty how do we decide
on a collective governance and then have
the bigger group that group of groups to
know how little Authority do they have
on the teams in the individuals right
because we are the ones making it up and
there is this difference that I'm
exploring in my own life like the war
versus the dance and I know sometimes
men or with people that I want them to
do what I want them to do because of the
outcome right I want people to stay at
home right now how dare you go out this
is my but it's like it's they're not
doing it to spite me and they're doing
it for their own their own best interest
if I am needing to be in control over
someone's life even though of course I
don't have control over their life but
my being wants to be in control of them
right I want like new governing rules
that will get you to behave in the way I
want you to behave instead of how do I
behave and when I won with Haven how do
we create this society that if there is
a good way to be it enables people to be
that way instead of enforcing it and
that is very again the individualistic
like what is my map and how do I
increase myself how do I find my groups
how do I help other people find their
groups and then how can the tools and
the technology facilitate that and the
process without ruling over it right
without saying you have to do X Y and D
to be part of this to be part of a group
you might need to but you could always
find a different group and there's
hopefully as few rules as possible over
the overarching bigger met a group that
is facilitated yeah that actually
reminded me of a conversation I was
having with Eric liberate mankind the
other day where we were talking about
he's got this concept of the monarchy he
calls it which is kind of this kind of
balance between the monarchy which is
kind of the well from my perspective I
see it as kind of like representing
order and then Anarchy representing
chaos although it's I know the model is
more complicated than that but that kind
of simplifies it down but one of the
points that came up in the conversation
was that if you have you know in kind of
oppressive dictatorships it actually
takes an enormous amount of energy to
force people to do things that they
don't know
do you want to do sew it in if you can
design a system that can actually
coordinate people and kind of harness
them then doing things that they most
enjoy you actually as a system become
capable of a huge amount more with much
less energy expenditure and well so it's
kind of like a win-win on all dimensions
and these these kind of systems that try
to kind of control populations through
like rigid dictatorial laws and stuff it
can only work temporarily and it's very
fragile because yeah it's just people
aren't happy they're being forced to do
what they have to do and that you have
to employ and pay people to enforce the
other people it's just enormous waste of
energy versus a system that's able to
coordinate people's differences and
unique interests so if we could do that
and maybe mapping can be a part of that
just helping people you've got interests
find the place that they can can
contribute that to the collective that's
interesting on the scale where on one
extreme there is dictatorship very
centralized which is telling people
exactly what to do and how and a
steering Center from central point like
everything people are unhappy and
motivation is very low and the overall
energy of the system is low and it's a
struggle to get anything done definitely
those systems tend to not last very long
or if they do it's it's costing like
enormous amount of blood basically and
then there are systems where yeah it's
like the free market metaphor is kind of
appropriate here because what we talked
about it's kind of similar it takes the
best of the free market idea which is
everyone is doing their thing and
somehow magically it produces like great
results for everyone which is not
necessarily true as we see in the world
there is stuff into it but
it's like the shadow of this idea is
also very strong and it's not being
talked too much about yeah whatever
reason the shadow being that the bottom
line as always people are forced to do
what to do something they are free to
choose what work they do but they still
need to do something because of this
dynamic of if I don't work I will not
have any money and then I will starve
and game over so there is that and if we
took oh yeah and free market is very
individualistic the basic thing about
free market is everyone is like an
individual and the magic happens between
individuals on some higher level and
what we are talking about is more like
yes everyone is doing our thing but we
also do the thing collectively and we
are able to recognize the collectives we
are in like local communities local are
you know local but interest groups and
the dynamic in those groups is not based
on just monetary values not on money
being passed in any direction just
thanks best interest yes I think here
I'm just gonna switch over to the the
next topic it as much time usually have
half an hour we all have about 20
minutes to to explore it of what could
game be actually create right now if it
had a thousand people like dedicated to
even just collecting their data and be
part of a conversation and then what
could those 1000 people create together
if they were able to volunteer let's say
three four hours a week month and then
also ten thousand dollars so you know
those thousand people putting in ten
dollars and you also have them
contributing some of their their
intellectual emotional physical labor
what could we create together and of
course everything's voluntary so we're
not like forcing a thousand people to do
that what could be created that would
entice
would be a natural attractor the game B
could do that maybe isn't individuals
working solely in their own their own
interests where that is able to weave
together to be the collective collective
benefit so if anyone has any ideas on
what we could do as an adjacent possible
maybe mapping I will let you start well
I think there's actually already some
interesting things that are happening
that wouldn't even necessarily need an
injection of cash that they're just kind
of naturally developing like the brain
project well they've already got a kind
of a beta product and they're developing
it pretty quickly they're hoping to have
it live so people can test it out fairly
soon I'm not sure what the exact date is
but part of their plan is to create a
questionnaire which can be shared with
the game B community that would ask a
bunch of different questions and they're
actually I've got a call with them
tomorrow and hunter to kind of discuss
to talk through what would what good
questions would be to ask people but you
know it could be things like you know
what what subjects do you think are
relevant to game a or can be what things
are you personally most interested in
which ones do you think are most
relevant versus not relevant and there's
lots of different types of questions
that could gather up data from the
community and then that could be kind of
plotted into a map graph type thing
where you know you've got all this data
suddenly represented in a way that
people can explore through it and they
can kind of find different communities
or they could find people who are
interested in different things well they
could kind of get a sense of what the
collective perspective is of game B just
through the way that data is visualized
so I think stuff like that is actually
already just in the process of
developing and I think in the next year
we'll see a few things like that
starting to pop up more to me the thing
that's most exciting about it I guess if
there was you know more participation
and this kind of continued to develop in
a positive way is that once we've got
some of those tools in place that it
could actually be beneficial to all the
different things that game B's doing so
you know game B projects can be online
tools all right all these different
groups they all share the same need to
be able to organize the con
they're doing allow people to find and
explore through that so I think I see
that as being like one of the golden
cane mapping is to produce something
that's actually useful to all the other
groups and to gain B as a whole so it's
kind of again the air like fractal and
its potential uses yeah ten thousand
people can get like produce a lot of
data which is like two things one is
gathering the data and then processing
and visualizing the data and results so
ten thousand people could start
immediately as soon as there is some
questionnaire just Philippine yeah I
think there's a lot of stuff that can be
done it is being done in a space for
less money that would cost any
individual ones did you learn or less
it's just about like not necessarily
dissipating the energy into eight
different projects and picking which
one's the best and focusing our energy
there like one of the things that we
could do is with a thousand people is do
something I had kind of talked to when I
first came into the game be space when
extinction rebellion was talking about
their citizen assemblies and I was like
why don't we want why are we fighting
the streets protesting to get our
governments to instill citizen
assemblies were the citizens we can just
hold assemblies like we could just get
those people you know gathering the
information on climate change present it
in a way that it's understandable for us
but there's things we can do without
going through the government and doing
something similarly with the thousand
people to so that it's different through
time zones have zoomed rooms and have it
be that we've asked these questions
right instead of it just being a survey
having conversations about what just
game fee means me what is game what is
what are the subject matters that I
think are important and then seeing the
interconnecting circle seeing where you
know why history is important to me and
it doesn't matter if history is
important everyone else else if it's
important to me how can I map that on to
game B and how can in Reverse having one
place we can go to both input and get
the people involved in game being both
the the people
actually involved right where we're I'm
a baby person contact me right and
there's people who maybe aren't game B
but their game be adjacent like Jordan
Peterson I don't think this maybe you've
been heard about game B but a lot of
people follow him and found through here
right Jordan Paul Moore and Jim Rock
more game B they they've identified
themselves as game B but they're also
game be adjacent and that people want to
watch all of their contents right and do
that I think having a way to know who's
been on whose podcast and which ones are
the most important what they talk about
instead of kind of giving everybody
homework in the game B space I can
already you first get here there's so
many podcasts I mean just to catch up
but then you realize Kent's never are
you gonna be able to watch all in Jordan
of all stuff and all his gym rat stuff
and you got even watch all my stuff and
I'm not like it's just too many
conversations participating in them but
having someone say hey watch this and
instead of hey everybody watch this I'm
able to actually distill the points to
you so you don't need to watch it and
it's catalogue so if we need the
relevant parts we can go to it and see
that and have that be more more relevant
than both just as people come into game
B and feel lost having a conversation
with them three four months out and
being like what is it that you were
looking for that we didn't give you and
then they're instrumental in helping
create that for the next three people
right because if what they were looking
for was the people they weren't easily
able to find them they can help the next
group of people by their people right so
I think using existing technology that's
already there like zoom and coordinating
it so that we don't need to create new
new technology yet until we have the
foundation of what it is we actually
would want in our game P platform what
is what are these overarching Solutions
of food water clothing what's currently
being done to pick what is the most
powerful project we could do after
conversation and then actually put
energy and time into creating that and
work through that process together and
even if it falls apart all parties who
think a lot of them evolve apart is that
we learn and if we do that transparently
we learning grow and it learns and grows
too and literally start anywhere and
keep improving it is the solution to
everything start somewhere and keep
improving it and do so openly and
transparently that would be one of the
questions on the questionnaire
about game B and so think about it and
what they see like what how did you get
here that's the most obvious and then
what piece of information you got you
was most enlightening to you it's like
which part of usually there is this
Jordan green house interview with
someone and then in about nine ten
minutes in there was this piece about
how to solve like the problem the
problem of cooperation and
incentivization I think it was a little
salt those apartments just struck me as
the most important thing ever in in this
space and everyone said ok for me it was
this point for me it was this interview
and this part of it like watch this five
minutes and you'll get more than if you
watched two hours of someone else's
which might be equally important but
then the five minutes is what it is all
about like Matthew has already been done
makes too much too much information and
knowing what conversations a big
proponent of conversations know what
conversations are going on when you're
invited to which ones can you watch all
gym rat stuff all Jordan halls it's
available it's definitely there it even
in the conversations face in the other
spaces what's what's there and I don't
want to watch hundreds and hundreds of
hours I want to know what is pertinent
right if I'm looking at competition
versus cooperation what are the top ten
talks on that that I could watch for
five minutes
right what one might be Jordan Hollow
meet Jordan Peterson one might be Eric
right like it depends on who actually
had the conversation and people we can
upload them into and take the videos
right be like whoo this is a like at the
highlighting right like this part is
really cool and the more we uploaded it
the more it would gain eyes instead of
just instead of I what I feel often
happens in the gay be space or people
giving each other homework right
everyone needs to read this everyone
needs to watch this and like there is no
read what you're interested in and then
bring that to the conversations that
your product bring not to the projects
but if we all have the same information
that's not
a silver that's not very like follow
your interest and then bring those
interests to your product
did you guys see my a chance did you see
the the tool that Nick had been building
where you kind of you put in like a
YouTube URL and then it scrapes through
and is able to kind of identify all the
most used words and it kind of
represents that honor on a graph did you
guys see that
yeah I saw this Legaspi shot off of this
and I was most impressed yeah it's
really interesting but yeah to me that's
just like a taster of some of the things
that we could and I had no idea he was
working on stuff like that I'd seen him
kind of participating in game B and then
that popped up and although wow that's
amazing
but yeah that's that's like a way of you
know using some software to kind of take
a video which would otherwise you'd have
to sit through the whole thing or read a
transcript but it just instantly
visualizes the content of that video and
like he's chosen a certain way to do
that but you could imagine all different
kinds of ways of visualizing things pick
up on different kinds of aspects of the
video so I think stuff like that's
really cool and then another thought I
had was an idea I was thinking about
awhile ago was you know imagine if as
you were exploring through the different
Facebook the game be Facebook group or
some of its sub groups if you came
across a post or a comment even and you
were like oh that really links well with
this other post this other comment
thread that I saw the other day if you
could just kind of highlight both of
them somehow and draw a link between
them and describe that relationship and
then if you imagine everyone was able to
do this simultaneously you could start
building up these kind of networks
between related content and I feel like
that's like another kind of mapping
related concept that could allow people
to to kind of help other people find
stuff and then also enable each other to
explore better if you come across an
interesting subject you just you can see
straight away that there's links to
other things that are related to that so
it's it's easier for you to find
so yeah that's something that's another
cool thing
could I don't know exactly you know my
views are on this is that I don't think
a lot of these innovations are going to
come through Facebook or were many of
these dominant platforms so I still kind
of think that we kind of we need some
other platform so I don't know how soon
that's going to happen but I could just
see all these different ideas and you
know there's so many people working on
it it just seems inevitable to me that
at some point we are going to make that
leap and it's just going to unlock an
enormous amount of different tools and
features and enable us to kind of
upper-level our collective intelligence
such a huge amount much she's learning I
would say could be very useful in this
aspect because as much as I trust people
to find links and connections that's
what our brains do after all we are good
at it not everyone would see the same
connections but collectively we can make
something beautiful but if it could be
helped with some kind of machine
learning application whatever stuff and
that for example the way I visualized it
if I was in the middle of a graph and I
said okay I want to know more about
governance um watching whatever then
around straightaway nodes of a nodes but
with most matching what I just asked the
system to tell me and then by kind of
weighted proximity think I could I
should be able to explore further and
further and the connections would the
banks by I think what Nick did stuff
like this it would be a basis for either
people doing the matching and thinking I
think Google algorithm works in some
similar right
by tracking alright
so yeah it can be done by a computer to
actually link everything and show it in
the most matching document to what you
want to see is this and then further the
most matching documents to the document
you just saw is this and this and
explanation like going on a fractal tree
that would be yeah yeah I just wanted we
only have about less than five minutes
left and so how we end this is we go
around and each person can say what they
think is the solution we count by third
you can comprehend a little bit that you
think is the most powerful you think
would be the most impactful or solving
what we are trying to solve which today
is mapping gave me I guess for me it
would be just creating that kind of the
most basic kind of mapping tool that's
it's got the most basic features
required but it's enough to enable
mapping of all different kinds of
subjects and doing it collaboratively it
sounds like a very complicated thing but
I actually think you could reduce it
down to a pretty simple set of rules and
dynamics it just needs to be really well
thought through and have a nice UI to
kind of match with that but I think if
we were able to do that in a very basic
level which I just think it could be
applied in all these different areas and
different scales as well so I think if
we could nail that initial design I
think that's it could grow into a kind
of an unlimited tree of other different
things yeah I totally agree
starting small something very simple
because yeah most important thing is to
just start even if it was a system with
one text box with enabling people to
write it down stuff and then connected
to some other
it'll be a start and that would be where
data starts being gathered and then it
can be always improved instead of
designing a perfect system from scratch
and doesn't start actually I really like
the work that you've been doing that you
demo to us in the call I think it was on
Thursday so remember there is with the
lines and stuff yeah I thought that was
really cool you still worried yes yes
furiously yeah I mean if you want to
chat about it some other time yeah
that's it sound like these very - of my
ideas as well as djibouti by the way
this is what I wanted to show you on our
last meeting which didn't work because I
couldn't screen sure about yes that's
something and yeah it's tough it's very
long time ago me wanting to do some
something that I no longer want to do
but still I have this idea in my head
that it needs to be expressed sometimes
there are ideas that yeah I heard this
so I do take up time with this but I
heard something like there are certain
ideas that want to express themselves
and they use humans as a vehicle of
enacting this this idea so that's I have
it stuck in my head and I just need to
finish it and I am totally definitely
happy to use that as some kind of but to
show it more to work on this and to be a
foundation of some useful tool at least
that would be perfect because as much as
I in the last few weeks
I watched most of the tools out there
the mapping tools including the brain
the seven vortex thing is also very cool
then it's beautiful but each of them is
I didn't think any of them that this is
the perfect thing and all of them are
missing like some part of some aspect
and obviously the least we can do like
the the noticed thing to do is to make a
tool that does it all yeah I love it cuz
I was I was writing down mind you gave
me a piece of it so I think although I
didn't really talk about it turn our
solutions one of its one of the tools
that in common would help with all of
the solutions as well it's like feeding
ourselves and getting that stuff ready
so we have more sovereignty that's
harder to do having a like a Yelp of
apps that we own together that we can
trust when someone works for a tool and
it's available that you know it exists
but what I love that you gave me is like
part of knowing what one feature has
another feature has that was definitely
know which one to use right of all the
team-building ones which one's the best
but she able to actually say what's
missing why don't I use this one because
then we can kind of create one that's
the best of all worlds right like what
is Facebook missing a lot but like that
you actually articulate it right that
the other ones have and to be able to
see when Nick creates something when
Matus crates anyone crates on the inner
out of game be that it's then able to be
available to the world in a way that
goes around Facebook and Google right
that's like hey we know it exists is it
trustworthy doesn't work and then how
can we improve it even if whether we own
it together or somebody else owns it how
can we actually continually improve this
so we can trust it more so it gets to be
the best of both worlds right it gets to
have all the features that we would need
it to have and at a price point we can't
afford which hopefully a zero but you
know anyway the app can sustain itself
the people can sustain itself but the
people using it have as little input as
possible because it's antivirus and the
more they're involved in it the better
benefit there is for everyone but we are
definitely at the our mark does anyone
have any closing statements before go
jump on the discord called all right
thank you James I Matus